理查德  我真不想承认  但我欠你的
Richard, it pains me to admit it, but I am in your debt.
没错  欠不少呢  如果你愿意开始付房租
Yes. Deeply. But if you'd like to start paying rent...
不是的  我是说我欠你句谢谢
No, no, no. I mean I owe you a debt of gratitude.
如果不是你敦促我
If you had not urged me
去参加这个试镜
to take this audition,
我也不会得到这个角色
I would never have gotten this part.
现在我要去试衣服了
Now I'm off to my wardrobe fitting.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
你去哪啊
Where are you off to?
我加入了一间三陪公司  我要去见客户
Oh, I signed up for an escort service. I have to meet a client.
什么  你说什么
What? A what?
我就是想看你到底有没有在听
I just wanted to see if you were listening.
我要去图书馆学习
I'm going to the library to study.
讨厌
Not cool.
-再见  凯特  -再见
- Bye, Kate. - Oh. Bye, bud.
吻别  这什么时候开始的
A goodbye kiss? When did that start?
刚刚啊
Just now.
我跟你一样惊讶啊
Yeah, no, I'm as surprised as you are.
也不算惊讶了
Well, I don't know if I'm surprised.
你是蛮待人亲的嘛
I mean, you are pretty lovable.
你养的女儿好
Well, you raised a great person, so...
你现在这么说  开始那几年你是没看着
Mm. You say that now. You weren't here for the beginning.
下次我就能看着了
Next time, I will be.
下次
Next time?
你是说你在考虑...
Are you saying that you're thinking about...
嗯  考虑了  还有我的工作
Yeah. About it, about my job,
我们是否准备好了
about whether we're ready,
或是这种事有没有合适的时机
if there's ever a right time.
从没有合适的时机  不过也没有不合适的时机
There never is, but there's never a wrong time, either.
-或许现在不行  -不是吧
- Except maybe now. - Really.
好了  我们回头再说
Okay, we'll talk about it later.
谁发现的尸体
So, who found the body?
流浪汉  艾德·特纳
Homeless guy, Ed Turner.
说他在垃圾箱里找瓶子时
Said he found her in this recycling bin
发现了尸体
when he was scavenging for bottles.
拿到他的口供了吗
We get Turner's statement?
没有  还没找到人呢
No, we haven't found him yet.
他用附近的付费电话报了警
He called 911 from a nearby payphone,
但我们赶到时  他已经走了
but when we got here, he was already gone.
她显然是没带身份证明了
Obviously, she's not carrying I.D.
那么  我猜我们不知道她的身份了
So, uh...I'm guessing we don't know who she is?
希望马上就能查到
Hopefully we will in a minute.
但现在  我能轻松说出死因
In the meantime, I can give you a pretty good idea of how she died.
勒毙
Manual strangulation.
大概在24到36小时之前
Probably 24 to 36 hours ago.
从尸僵情况看
Based on lividity,
她一死就被塞进了垃圾箱
she was put in the dumpster right after she was killed.
脚上有擦伤
Abrasions on her feet.
腿上有泥点
Mud spatter on her legs.
她是跑过来的  有人在追她
She was running. Someone was chasing her.
然后抓住了她  杀了她
And then caught her, killed her,
还塞进了那边的垃圾箱
and stuffed her in that dumpster over there.
而且她穿着睡衣
And she's wearing a nightgown.
不可能从很远的地方来
She couldn't have come from very far.
我让警员拿她的照片去排查
I'll have unis show her photo around,
看看有没有人认得她
try to find someone who recognizes her.
排查寻找可能
Canvass... see if there are any witnesses
-看到事情经过的目击者  -好的
- who might have seen what happened. - Okay.
蕾妮  你没事吧
Lanie, are you okay?
嗯  就是她有种...熟悉感
Yeah. It's just something about her... something familiar.
怎么  你认识她吗
What, like you know her?
不  我绝对不认识她
No, I definitely don't know her.
如果她有案底  我们就能查清身份了
If she's in the system, we can find out who she is.
苏珊·瓦茨  纽约  维斯塔尔人
Susan Watts... born in Vestal, New York.
高中辍学
High-school dropout.
多次被捕
Multiple arrests...
空头支票骗钱  轻盗窃罪  曾因持毒被抓
Check kiting, petty larceny, bust for possession.
最后一次被捕被送去了阿尔比恩监狱
The last one got her sent to Albion,
但她六个月前获释了
but she was released six months ago.
之后有什么记录吗
Anything since then?
没有  那是她最后一次跟执法部门打交道了
No, that was her last-known contact with law enforcement.
那么已知联络人呢
What about known associates?
或许她的朋友知道她被谁杀了
Maybe she was hanging out with someone that knows who killed her.
没有列出联系人
No associates listed,
但我有苏珊·瓦茨的地址
but I do have Susan Watts' address.
-有事吗  -贝克特探长  纽约警局
- Can I help you? - Detective Beckett, NYPD.
我要问你几个关于苏珊·瓦茨的问题
I need to ask you a few questions about Susan Watts.
怎么  出什么事了吗
Why? Did something happen?
我七年前就戒烟了
I quit smoking seven years ago,
但我现在真的很想抽一支
and I really want a cigarette right now.
卡特里娜  你最后见到苏珊或跟她通话是什么时候
Katrina, when was the last time you saw Susan or talked to her?
大概三个月前吧  她搬出去时
Maybe three months ago, about the time she moved out.
她搬了出去
She moved out?
她去了哪
Where'd she go?
不知道  她没住这儿多久
I don't know. She didn't stay here long.
不到六个月
Less than six months.
她有什么朋友  男朋友
Did she have any friends, boyfriends,
或一起玩的人吗
people that she partied with?
苏珊不是那样的人  现在不是了
Susan wasn't like that. Not anymore.
我发了求室友的广告  她回应了
I posted an ad looking for a roommate, and she answered.
她坦诚自己曾是瘾君子
She was up front that she used to be an addict,
蹲过监狱
been in prison.
但她发誓那都是过去的事了
But she swore she was done with all that.
事实证明  她还是个完美的室友呢
She actually turned out to be the dream roommate.
真没想到
Go figure.
她为什么搬走了
And why did she move out?
她得到了份很棒的新工作
She got some great new job.
-什么工作  -不清楚
- What kind of job? - I'm not sure,
但突然间
but all of a sudden,
她就买得起好衣服  住得起好公寓了
she could afford great clothes and a way nicer place,
所以她走了  我替她开心
so off she went. I was happy for her.
感觉她真的扭转了人生
Seemed like she had really turned her life around.
你还了解这份新工作的什么情况
What else can you tell me about this new job?
她为谁工作
Who did she work for?
她没说过
She never told me.
她对此还挺神秘的
She was actually kind of secretive about it.
排查毫无结果
So, the canvass isoming up empty.
既找不到艾德·特纳  那个报警的
There's no sign of Ed Turner, dude who called 911.
没有目击者  也没人认识苏珊·瓦茨
No witnesses, and no one who knows Susan Watts,
这很奇怪
which is weird,
因为她如果不是就住在附近
because why would she be running down that alley in her jams
又怎么会穿着睡衣在小巷里跑
if she didn't live in the neighborhood?
知道还有什么奇怪吗
You know what else is weird?
我完全查不到她的这份工作
I can't find anything on this job that she had.
没有报税单什么的吗
No W-2s or 1099s?
也没有社保扣款
or social security withholding,
她的工资肯定是用现金结算的
so she must've been paid in cash.
也许她做的是非法工作
So maybe her job was illegal,
也许这就是她被杀的原因之一
and that might be part of the reason she was killed.
我找到的唯一与就业有关的资料
The only reference I found regarding employment
是一个叫"新起点视野"的地方
was a place called NewStart Horizons.
听着像节食计划似的
Sounds like a diet plan.
按理说是的
You would think so,
不过这其实是个
Uh, but it's a job-placement organization
为坐过牢的女性介绍工作的组织
for women who've been incarcerated
总部就在本市
based right here in the city.
他们去监狱探视时认识了苏珊
Susan met with them when they visited the prison.
也许就是他们为她安排了那份工作
So maybe they placed her in that job,
他们也许知道她搬去了哪里
And they might know where she moved to.
我会跟贝克特再说下新起点的情况
I'll loop Beckett in on NewStart Horizons.
-怎么了  -首先
- So, what's up? - Well, for one thing,
我在死者的头发中发现了这个
I found this in the victim's hair.
羽毛
Feather.
可能是被絮或羽绒枕之类的东西
Probably from bedding or a down pillow or something.
所以她当时可能正在睡觉  被人赶出了房子
So maybe she was in bed and got chased out of her house.
凶手可能是她认识的人  也许是男友
Killer could've been somebody she knew, maybe a boyfriend.
这女人到底什么情况
What's the story with this woman?
问这个干什么
Why do you ask?
是不是这么回事
Is it something like this?
她先是犯了点小法
She was in trouble with the law,
然后重拾了自我  找了份很好的工作
then she gets her act together, finds a great job,
可你们怎么也查不出到底是什么工作
but damned if you can figure out what that job is.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
还记得帕姆·霍奇斯吗
Do you remember Pam Hodges?
当然  怎么忘得了
Yeah. How could I forget her?
她跟你长得一模一样
She looked just like you.
那是被人为改造的
That's how she was made to look.
帕姆·霍奇斯就跟我刚说的情况一样
Pam Hodges had the same story,
只不过她是个坦帕市的妓女
except she was a hooker in tampa.
莫名其妙就突然改邪归正了
Out of nowhere, she gets herself straightened out,
找了份很好的工作  然后被杀了  勒毙
gets a great job, then gets killed -- strangled.
对  但方法不同
Yeah, but not in the same way.
帕姆是被卡尔·马修斯用电线勒死的
Pam was strangled with wire by Carl Matthews,
可我们已经将他绳之以法了
but we put him away.
所以帕姆·霍奇斯跟苏珊·瓦茨有什么关系
So, what does Pam Hodges have to do with Susan Watts?
我觉得她们有关联
I think they're connected.
你好  我是纽约警局的贝克特探长
Excuse me. Hi, I'm detective Beckett, NYPD.
我需要找人询问点情况
I need to speak with someone
关于你们的一位顾客  苏珊·瓦茨
about one of your clients, Susan Watts.
我跟主任联系一下
Let me contact the director.
好的
Okay.
不好意思
Uh...excuse me.
蕾妮  有什么发现
Lanie, hey, what do you got?
我正跟哈维一起
I'm here with Javi,
我想我知道为什么会觉得苏珊·瓦茨眼熟了
and I think I know why Susan Watts looked familiar.
她做过面部整容手术
She had cosmetic surgery on her face.
动得不多
Way less extreme,
但跟帕姆·霍奇斯做过的非常相似
But a lot like what Pam Hodges had done.
帕姆·霍奇斯
Pam Hodges?
是一样的面颊植入物  一样的技术
It's the same cheek implants, the same technique.
凯特  我认为苏珊·瓦茨的手术
Kate, I think Susan Watts' surgery
是由同一名医生操刀的
was performed by the same doctor.
凯莉·尼曼医生
Dr. Kelly Nieman?
来  用我的笔吧
Please, let me offer you a pen.
不用了  谢谢
No. Thank you.
我们只是来问几个问题的
We're just here to ask you a few questions.
恕我冒昧  你的脸真是太美了  探长
Oh, can I just say, you have an amazing face, detective.
我无法证明  但我的直觉是这是尼曼的手法
I can't prove it, but my gut says this is Nieman's work.
她与帕姆·霍奇斯和丹尼尔·桑托斯被害有关
She was in on the murders of Pam Hodges and Daniel Santos,
但你没能将她定罪
and you could never nail her for it,
也许这次可以了
maybe this time you can.
凯特  你还在听吗
Kate, are you still there?
蕾妮  不只是你的直觉
Lanie, uh, it's not just your gut.
凯莉·尼曼的确跟这事有关  我正看着她呢
Kelly Nieman is a part of this, and I'm looking right at her.
等等  凯莉·尼曼跟这事有关
Wait... Kelly Nieman is mixed up in this?
我以为她已经逃出国了
I thought she left the country.
她回来了
She's back.
不过新起点视野的主任声称
Though the director at NewStart Horizons
尼曼医生从没见过苏珊·瓦茨
claims that Dr. Nieman never met Susan Watts.
可现在苏珊死了
Only now Susan is dead,
而凯莉·尼曼是新起点的主要资助人之一
and Kelly Nieman is a major donor of NewStart Horizons.
没错  不可能是巧合
Yeah, it can't be a coincidence.
我能做些什么
What can I do?
留意电话就好  有消息我告诉你
Just stay close to the phone. I'll be in touch.
凯特  你有多确定
Kate, how sure are you
凯莉·尼曼跟苏珊·瓦茨的案子有关
that Kelly Nieman is connected with the Susan Watts case?
有很多线索都指向她  长官
A lot of things point to her, sir.
就像帕姆·霍奇斯和丹尼尔·桑托斯的案子一样
As it did with Pam Hodges and Daniel Santos,
但没有切实的证据
but no actual proof.
当时  你觉得3XK
At the time, you felt that 3xk
也许跟那些谋杀案有关
might have played a part in those murders.
你觉得这案子也跟他有关吗
Do you think he played a part in this one, too?
我现在还没有任何证据  长官
I don't have any evidence of it yet, sir,
我们也没找到任何切实证据
and we haven't found any actual proof
能证明杰瑞·泰森还活着
that Jerry Tyson is still alive.
也许凯莉·尼曼本人
It's possible that Kelly Nieman
就是个连环杀手
is a serial killer in her own right.
她非常狡猾  并且反社会的程度
She's as shrewd and high functioning
比他更甚
of a sociopath as he ever was.
如果尼曼医生跟这起谋杀案有关
If Dr. Nieman is involved in this murder,
我要如何确保
How can I make sure
她不会再次从我们手中逃走
that she doesn't slip through our fingers again?
你可以把卡塞尔调回来当顾问
You could bring Castle in to consult on this case.
不行  警探
No, detective.
长官  他对尼曼的案子了若指掌
Sir, he knows the Nieman case inside and out.
他能帮上大忙
He could be a huge asset.
我有意同意你的意见  不过
Well, I am inclined to agree with you, but...
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle...
只能参与这一件案子
works on this case only.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
先别急着谢我
Don't thank me yet.
还得让地检官也同意才行
Still have to get the D.A. on board.
打扰了  长官
Excuse me, captain.
我们查了凯莉·尼曼
We looked into Kelly Nieman.
她在哥斯达黎加有家外科诊所
She has a surgical clinic in Costa Rica,
但六个月前  通过一个外科整容集团
but she also began seeing patients right here in this city
她也开始接收市里的病人了
Six months ago through a cosmetic surgery group.
具体什么地方
Where?
圣西蒙医院  八楼
St. Simon's hospital, eighth floor.
帕姆·霍奇斯被谋杀了
Pam Hodges was murdered,
还有丹尼尔·桑托斯
and so was Daniel Santos,
唯一与他们两个有关联的人就是你
and the only person that they have in common is you.
那我有什么动机去杀人呢
What possible motive would I have for killing anyone?
她主动提出去当监狱的医生
She volunteered as a prison doctor.
不仅如此  她还治疗了杰端·泰森
Not only that, she treated Jerry Tyson.
她肯定是泰森的女朋友
She's got to be Tyson's girlfriend.
他把他知道的都教给她
He taught her everything he knew.
我们晚了一步  尼曼清空了这里跑了
We got here too late. Nieman cleared out. She's gone.
你以为你搞清楚了这一切  可你并没有
You think you've got this all figured out, but you don't.
*我们还会再见*
*We'll meet again*
*虽不知何地*
*Don't know where*
*虽不知何时*
*Don't know when*
*但我知道*
*But I know*
我们又见面了
We meet again.
就像歌里唱的那样
Like the song says.
凯特·贝克特
Kate Beckett.
如此精致的容貌
Such lovely features.
技艺高超的人能对你大展拳脚啊
What skilled hands could do with you.
我对咨询可没兴趣
I'm not interested in a consultation.
我也没有
Neither am I.
你应该知道你认为我参与了
You do know your little theory that I played a role
那些凶杀案的想法  损害了我的业务还有名誉
in those deaths damaged my practice, my reputation.
但我真心觉得这都过去了
But I can truly say that's all in the past now
而且我对你并没有恶意
and I bear you no malice.
好吧  真让人松了一口气
Well, that's a relief.
关于苏珊·瓦茨你都知道些什么
What can you tell me about Susan Watts?
我没怎么听过这个名字
I'm not familiar with that name.
她是新起点视野的员工
She was a client at NewStart Horizons.
还有很多其他的女性都是
Many women are.
你从来都没在那见过她吗
So you never met her there?
我是新起点视野的资助人  探长
I donate to NewStart Horizons, detective.
但我不常待在那
But it's not where I spend my time,
我也不认识苏珊·瓦茨
and I don't know Susan Watts.
这个能让你记起来吗
Does this refresh your memory?
她找了个实际上并不存在的工作
She got a job that apparently doesn't exist.
她也在你这里接受了整容手术
She also had cosmetic surgery performed by you.
你肯定是搞错了
You must be mistaken.
我不会忘记人的脸  特别是我动过刀的
I never forget a face, especially if I cut it.
我想你不会介意我
So I suppose you won't mind if I take a look
为了保险起见查看你的病人档案
at your patient records just to be sure.
当然不会
Of course not.
我只是需要看一下法官签署的法庭命令
I just need to see a court order signed by a judge.
我会拿来的
I'll get one.
希望不会是基于随意的猜测
Not based on casual suspicions,
不过好像你也就只有这些
which is all you seem to have.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
一份临别的礼物
A parting gift?
一个面部复苏仪  我自己生产的
A facial-rejuvenation kit. My own product line.
不用了  谢谢
No. Thank you.
你确定  你看上去有点疲惫
You sure? You look a bit fatigued.
怎么了  贝克特
What's up, Beckett?
凯莉·尼曼不承认她认识苏珊·瓦茨
Kelly Nieman just denied knowing Susan Watts,
我需要证据证明她在说谎
and I need proof that she's lying.
我还没找到
Well, I haven't found any yet.
但到目前为止  没有人在新起点视野
But so far, nobody at NewStart Horizons
看到过她们在一起
remembers seeing them together,
也没法医证据能把尼曼和谋杀案联系起来
and there's no forensic evidence that ties Nieman to the murder.
监视她
Put a surveillance detail on her,
把圣西蒙医院的监控录像调出来
and pull security video from St. Simon's hospital.
也许苏珊在这儿见过尼曼
Maybe Susan visited Nieman here
或者来预约过
or came in for an appointment.
我马上就去做
I'll get right on it,
但这需要梳理好几周的监控录像
but you're talking about weeks of footage to comb through,
即使圣西蒙医院让我们查看的话
and that's even if St. Simon's lets us have it.
但还是有些好消息
But I do have some good news for you.
什么
What?
地方检察院同意让卡塞尔
The D.A. signed off on Castle
和我们一起办这个案子
working this case with us.
等你回来他就能办案了
He'll be here ready to jump in by the time you get back.
你真觉得尼曼与苏珊·瓦茨的谋杀案有关吗
Do you really think Nieman's behind Susan Watts' murder?
说不准  她是个冷血的人
Couldn't tell. She's got ice water in her veins.
不过我认为凯莉·尼曼
Although I'll bet Kelly Nieman
肯定不是那个在巷子里动手的人
wasn't in the alleyway doing the dirty work.
上次  她有个共犯
Last time, she had an accomplice,
一个中间人  帮她杀人
a proxy -- someone who did the killing for her.
那这次谁是那个中间人呢
So, who's the proxy this time?
伙计们  我们有线索了
Hey, guys. We got something.
没有法院的命令
The hospital won't share security footage
医院不让我们调取监控录像
without a court order.
但我找到了一个街道摄像头
But I was able to locate a street cam
可以看到医院的入口
with a view of the hospital entrance.
于是我们就查看了里面的录像
So, we started rolling through it,
很快  我们就找到了这个
and in no time, we ran across this.
她拿着一个凯莉·尼曼的礼品袋
She's carrying a Kelly Nieman gift bag.
就是她  那人绝对就是苏珊·瓦茨
Well, that's her. That's definitely Susan Watts.
除了一个时间线问题
Except there's a timeline problem.
这段录像是昨天下午的
This footage is from yesterday afternoon.
在苏珊·瓦茨死后
After Susan Watts was already dead,
所以那肯定不是她
so this can't be her.
那不是苏珊·瓦茨吗
That's not Susan Watts?
好吧  要么就是疯狂的巧合
All right, then either by some insane coincidence,
凯莉·尼曼有另一个
Kelly Nieman has another patient
和苏珊·瓦茨长得一模一样的病人
who looks exactly like Susan Watts...
要么就是尼曼出于某种原因用手术
Or Nieman surgically changed that woman
让那个女人看上去就像苏珊·瓦茨
to look like Susan Watts for some reason.
不管怎样  我们都要弄清楚这个女人在哪
Either way, we've got to figure out where this woman is.
天哪
Oh, my god.
看谁在开车
Look who's driving.
是3XK
It's 3XK.
杰瑞·泰森
Jerry Tyson.
他还活着
He's alive.
大家听着
Listen up, people.
这名女性现在处境非常危险
This woman is in grave danger.
她昨天离开了圣西蒙医院
She left St. Simon's hospital yesterday,
我们急需找到她
and we urgently need to find her.
她是凯莉·尼曼医生的病人
She is a patient of Dr. Kelly Nieman.
尼曼不配合我们
Nieman is not cooperating,
所以排查这所医院
so canvass the hospital.
那肯定有人知道她是谁
Someone there has to know who she is.
调查这辆车
And work this vehicle.
找到这辆车  我们就能找到她
We find the truck, we find the woman
还有车上和她一起的这个男人
along with the man she took a ride with.
他就是杰瑞·泰森  又叫3XK
That man is Jerry Tyson, also known as 3XK.
我确定在座的各位没有人比
And I am sure that no one here
卡塞尔更加了解他
is more familiar with him than Castle.
也不能完全这么说
A...dubious distinction.
3XK  三重杀手
3XK, the triple killer.
这么称他是因为他每次都杀三个  像最近的
So named because he kills his victims in groups of three --
这位被害人一样的金发女人  苏珊·瓦茨
blondes like his latest victim, Susan Watts.
3XK最初的凶杀案一直没破
The original 3XK killings were unsolved
而且很快凶手就停手了
and stopped soon after they started.
不过四年前  又出现了一名被害人
But then four years ago, another victim showed up.
三重杀手回来了
The triple killer is back.
我们要找的人叫马库斯·盖茨
The man that we're looking for is Marcus Gates.
纽约警局
NYPD!
我们当时无法证明马库斯·盖茨就是3XK
Now, we couldn't prove that Marcus Gates was 3XK.
不过他的狱友  杰瑞·泰森
But his cellmate, Jerry Tyson,
同意帮我们抓住盖茨
agreed to help us put Gates away
条件是让他提前出狱
in exchange for an early release.
可后来证明这次交易很不合算
That turned out to be not such a good deal.
不是马库斯·盖茨
It's not Marcus Gates.
是他  他才是三重杀手
It was him all along. He's the real triple killer.
当我们意识到杰瑞·泰森才是3XK的时候
By the time we realized that Jerry Tyson was 3XK,
已经太晚了
it was too late.
后来我们又差一点抓到他
We got close again
泰森用从莱恩警探那偷来的枪杀了人
when Tyson used the gun he stole from Detective Ryan in a homicide,
之后就消失了
then he dropped out of sight.
但并没有消失太久
But not for long.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle,
你因涉嫌谋杀泰莎·霍顿而被捕了
you're under arrest for the murder of Tessa Horton.
这一切都是你干的  你杀了泰莎
You did this. Y-you killed Tessa.
是你杀了泰莎
You killed tessa.
你连一个晚上都活不过
You will not last the night.
他没死
He's not dead.
你朝他开了枪  他死了  都结束了
You shot him. He's dead. It's over.
暂时结束而已
For now.
我也希望我的怀疑是没有根据的
I wish I could say my doubts were unfounded.
为什么有人会杀害克隆版埃斯波西托和蕾妮
Why would someone kill clones of Esposito and Lanie?
凯莉·尼曼在下一盘更大的棋
Kelly Nieman is playing a much deeper game.
3XK的档案呢
Where are the 3XK files?
我没领走任何档案
I didn't check out any files.
不光是泰森的档案没了
It's not just Tyson's files that are gone.
所有3XK案件死者的报告
Lab work, DNA, tissue samples
实验室化验单  DNA和组织样本全被蕾妮取走了
of every 3XK victim were checked out by Lanie.
只不过不是真的蕾妮
Only not the real Lanie.
当时
Now, at the time,
我们并不是非常确定泰森就是幕后黑手
we weren't certain that Tyson was behind it all.
我们都不知道他是否还活着  不过现在知道了
We didn't even know if he was alive, but we do now.
但我们这次运气不错
But we might have gotten lucky.
苏珊·瓦茨好像是从泰森那逃了出来
It looks like Susan Watts escaped from Tyson,
迫使他不得不在小巷里杀了她
forcing him to kill her in the alley
并把她尸体遗弃在那
and leave her body there,
这就说明他大意了  出现了疏忽
which means he got careless, he made mistakes.
我们要利用现在的优势  找到这个女人
Let's press our advantage and find this woman
以免她成为他的下一个被害人
before she becomes his next victim.
你看上去不错  卡塞尔先生
You look well, Mr. Castle.
不过你脸上的皱纹应该处理处理了
Though your palpebral folds could use some tending.
你不是不再办案了吗
I thought you stopped working on cases.
为了你  我破例一次
For you, I made an exception.
你们要知道  我来这是出于礼貌
Please know I'm here as a courtesy.
当然了  这个女人是谁
I'm sure you are. Who is this woman?
你可别说你不认识她
And don't say you don't know her.
她拿着的是你的礼品包
She is carrying your swag bag.
这并不能证明她是我的病人
That doesn't prove she's a patient.
你是说她不是你的病人吗
Are you saying she's not a patient?
我是说我不能回答  否则就违反了保密条约
I'm saying I can't answer that. I'd be breaking confidentiality.
没有违反  你甚至有义务回答这个问题
Which you would be free to do, even obliged to do,
特别是在你的病人有生命危险的情况下
especially if a patient's life is in danger.
她上了杰瑞·泰森的车
She took a ride with Jerry Tyson.
没有比这更危险的事了
It doesn't get more dangerous than that.
可是杰瑞·泰森已经死了  所以那不可能是他
Except Jerry Tyson is dead. Therefore, that can't be him.
真的吗
Really?
那他是谁  我们去哪里能找到他
Then who is he, and where do we find him?
我也不知道啊
I really couldn't say.
我知道你为什么来这
I know why you're here.
是为了看看我们掌握了什么
To see what we have.
你们掌握了什么跟我无关
What you have is irrelevant to me.
我是无辜的  没有做任何错事
I'm innocent of any wrongdoing.
如果你是无辜的
If you're innocent,
那你为什么不告诉我们这个女人的名字
then why won't you give us this woman's name?
况且你越不说  越显得有罪
Especially when not giving it makes you look guilty.
任何一个法官都会认为这就是杰瑞·泰森
Any judge we take this to will see this man is Jerry Tyson.
我们会得到法院的强制令从而得知那个病人的名字
We will be granted a court order for that patient's name.
所以你最好现在就告诉我
So you can give it to me now,
否则我们会在一个小时后
or I'll see you in an hour in your hospital
带着许多警察去你的医院
with a dozen police officers.
你来选吧
Your choice.
她的名字叫艾米·巴瑞特
Her name is Amy Barrett.
查查那个名字  快
Run that name. Go.
这么说你承认艾米·巴瑞特是你的病人了
So you admit that Amy Barrett is a patient of yours.
她住在哪
Where does she live?
我会让我办公室的人把她的联系信息发给你们
I'll have my office send her contact information.
她为什么要整容
Why did she want surgery?
她想变得更漂亮
She wanted to enhance her appearance.
她最后整成苏珊·瓦茨的样子
And it's just an amazing coincidence
完全是一个巧合吗
she ended up looking exactly like Susan Watts?
我刚才说了  我不知道那个人是谁
As I've said before, I don't know who that is.
可她们俩一模一样
And yet they look identical.
无论你想干什么
Whatever you're up to,
无论泰森想干什么
whatever tyson is up to,
都会被我们阻止的
we will stop it.
杰瑞·泰森已经死了
Jerry Tyson is dead.
我还有整容手术要做
And I have a surgery scheduled.
凯莉·尼曼办公室发给我们的联系信息已经过时了
Contact info that Kelly Nieman's office sent us was out of date.
艾米两个月前就搬走了
Amy moved out of her place two months ago.
还在查她搬去了哪
Still trying to figure out where.
就像苏珊·瓦茨一样
Just like Susan Watts.
还有其它共同的地方
That's not all she had in common.
艾米·巴瑞特在亚利桑那州长大  16岁离家出走
Amy Barrett grew up in Arizona. Ran away at 16.
四处漂流  被逮捕过很多次
She drifted around. Multiple arrests.
她跟新起点视野有什么联系吗
She have any connection to NewStart Horizons?
我没有找到
Not that I can tell.
尼曼是在制造被害人
Nieman's creating his victims.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
为杰瑞·泰森
For Jerry Tyson.
她们就像是克隆的
They're like clones.
都是金发  而且很漂亮
They're blond and pretty,
刚好是泰森喜欢的类型
Just the way Tyson likes them.
尼曼发现了这些可怜的女人
Nieman finds these poor women,
迷失了方向  没人会寻找她们
lost souls that no one is gonna miss,
于是她重新塑造了她们
and she remakes them.
她为3XK重新打扮了她们
She grooms them for 3XK.
我们找到了那辆车
Yo. We got the truck.
托瑞从另一处监控上找到的
Tory picked it up on another street cam.
拍到了车牌照
Got a license plate.
车属于一个叫迈克尔·布德罗的人
Vehicle belongs to a guy named Michael Boudreau.
有地址吗
We got an address?
离发现苏珊·瓦茨尸体的四个街区
Yeah, four blocks from where Susan Watts was found.
我们走
Let's go.
肯定是这里
This is definitely the place.
你认为这和迈克尔·布德罗有什么联系
How do you think Michael Boudreau figures in?
也许他是泰森的同谋
He may be Tyson's accomplice.
迈克尔·布德罗  纽约警察  开门
Michael Boudreau, NYPD! Open the door!
站住  纽约警察
Freeze! NYPD!
双手举起来
Let me see your hands!
远离窗户
Step away from the window.
转身
Turn around.
杰瑞·泰森  你被逮捕了
Jerry Tyson, you are under arrest.
我愿付出一切审审他
What I wouldn't give to be in that box with Jerry Tyson.
我们抓到了他
Well, we arrested him.
他要蹲大牢了  我很满足
He's going away. I'm good with that.
是啊  但他没拿着你的枪
Yeah, but he didn't take your gun
去杀别人
and get someone killed with it.
是啊
Yeah.
莱恩
Ryan.
你们找到艾米·巴瑞特了吗
Did you find any sign of Amy Barrett?
还没  但鉴证组在找她是否留下指纹
Not yet, but CSU's pulling prints to see if she was here.
他们也在搜查床上用品和枕头
They're also checking bedding and pillows
看是不是和蕾妮在苏珊·瓦茨头发上
to see if it matches that feather
找到的羽毛吻合
that Lanie found in Susan Watts' hair.
迈克尔·布德罗又是什么情况
Well, what's the story on Michael Boudreau?
根据他的工资单和其他物品
Well, based on his pay stubs and some other stuff,
他六个月前从爱荷华州来纽约
he came from Iowa six months ago.
在建筑工地上班
Works in construction.
-那他现在在哪  -我们不知道
- Well, where is he now? - We don't know.
我们也不知道他和
We also don't know his connection
杰瑞·泰森之间的关系
to Jerry Tyson, either.
好的  继续向我汇报情况
All right, uh, keep me posted.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
莱恩  看看这个
Yo, Ryan. Check it out.
在床底下发现这个
Found this under the bed.
看看这张照片
Look at the photo.
艾米·巴瑞特
Amy Barrett.
因为这是她的手机
Because it's her phone.
她来过这
She was here.
问题是  她人在哪  泰森对她做了什么
Question is, where is she now and what did Tyson do to her?
我从没想过会有这么一天
I never thought this day would come.
不仅可以证明杰瑞·泰森还活着
Not only can we prove Jerry Tyson is alive,
而且将他扣押了
but we have him in custody.
但是我们没有确凿的证据
What we don't have is a smoking gun.
那间公寓找不到任何证据吗
There's no evidence at the apartment?
没有证据指证他犯罪
Nothing to indicate foul play,
而且我们不能用以前的罪行起诉他
and we can't charge him for his past crimes,
他的犯罪记录都不见了
not with his records missing.
还有汽车旅馆那件事可以起诉
We have him at the motel.
他袭击了莱恩
He attacked Ryan.
把我五花大绑拿枪指着我
He tied me up at gunpoint.
绑架  加重袭警罪
Kidnapping, the aggravated assault of a police officer,
而且用警枪可是重罪
and use of a gun during a felony.
可以利用这点起诉
That will work.
我们抓到他了
So we got him.
就有足够时间将他和艾米·巴瑞特
That'll buy us enough time to tie him to Amy Barrett,
苏珊·瓦茨的案子联系到一起立案
Susan Watts, build a real case.
我们知道了他是如何认识艾米的
We figured out how he might have crossed paths with Amy.
在来纽约之前
Before she came to New York,
她曾在俄亥俄一家非营利性诊所
she was being treated for substance abuse
因为药物滥用接受治疗
at a nonprofit clinic in Ohio.
别告诉我  凯莉·尼曼就是捐献人
Don't tell me -- Kelly Nieman's a donor.
捐献给了那个机构
To that organization
还捐献给全国各地的许多人
and dozens of others just like it across the country.
她和泰森合谋
She and Tyson are in this together.
搭档
Partners.
连环杀手小队
A serial-killer team.
她一定是招募了这些女孩
She must have recruited these women,
承诺给她们好工作  新外貌和美好未来
promised them a great job, a new look, and a bright future.
是的  被杰瑞·泰森杀死的未来
Yeah, a future that ended with Jerry Tyson.
据我们所知
For all we know,
她和泰森已经作案数月  甚至数年了
she and Tyson have been doing this for months, years.
他也许很聪明
He probably got smart,
在我们永远找不到的地方处理尸体
disposed of the bodies where we'd never find them.
直到苏珊·瓦茨逃出来了
Until Susan Watts got away.
我们会将他绳之以法  莱曼也是
We're gonna bring him down. Nieman, too.
他有说什么吗
Has he said anything yet?
还没  但要开口了
Not yet. But he's about to.
是应该来感受一下气氛
Should really soak up the ambiance.
接下的时间你要待的地方就数这里最舒适
This is the nicest room you're gonna be seeing for quite a while.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
你当时在公寓里
You were at the apartment.
这是我第一次见到这么性感的女警察
First time I saw a cop who was a woman of your hotness.
第一次  你不认识我了吗
The first me? You don't know me?
不认识
N-no.
两个都不认识
I don't know either one of you.
好啊  想玩游戏是吧
Okay, fine, if you want to play that game.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
我是贝克特探长
I'm Detective Beckett.
你好吗  女士
How do you do, ma'am?
我是说真的
Um...I got to be honest,
这是个天大的误会
this is a big misunderstanding.
那为什么你要逃
Then why did you try to run?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
对不起  我想当时慌了吧
I'm sorry. I panicked, I guess.
说真的  我也做过非法的事
Honestly, I haven't always been on the right side of the law.
还用你说
You don't say?
说说艾米·巴瑞特的事
Tell us about Amy Barrett.
可爱的女孩
Oh, sweet girl.
艾米在公寓里做什么
What was Amy doing at the apartment?
她和我住在一起
She stays there with me.
她是你什么人  女朋友吗
What is she, your girlfriend?
我不想确立我们之间是什么关系
I don't want to put a label on what we have.
她现在在哪
Where is she now?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
我又没监视她
It's not like I keep tabs on her.
那苏珊·瓦茨呢  她也是你女朋友吗
What about Susan Watts? Is she your girlfriend, too?
不是
No.
我不认识她
I-I don't know her.
迈克尔·布德罗在哪
Where's Michael Boudreau?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你为什么在他的公寓  开着他的车
Why were you at his apartment, driving his truck?
拜托  我才是迈克尔·布德罗
Come on. Man, I'm Michael Boudreau.
你是迈克尔·布德罗
You're Michael Boudreau?
是的
Yeah.
什么
What?
是啊  不然你们认为我是谁
Yeah. Who -- who else would I be?
杰瑞·泰森
Jerry Tyson.
我总是会遇到这样的情形
Y-- I-I get that from time to time.
是啊  那没什么好惊讶的
Yeah, well, that's not surprising,
因为你跟泰森长得一模一样
considering you look exactly like Tyson
而跟迈克尔·布德罗的照片却一点也不像
and nothing like this photo of Michael Boudreau.
对此你作何解释
So, why don't you explain that?
我确实对面貌进行了一点加工
Truth is I got a little work done.
这里依然能看到一个小伤疤
You can still see a teeny scar here.
还有这里
And here.
-你做了整容手术  -是的
- You got cosmetic surgery... - Yeah.
为了和连环杀手长得一样吗
...to look like a serial killer?
我一直都不喜欢自己的长相
I never liked how I looked,
后来遇见一个优秀的整容医生
and so I met this great surgeon,
她给了我一张新的面孔
and she just gave me a new face.
有趣的是  自从我变成他的样子之后
The funny thing is, I've never felt more like myself
我觉得自己终于找回自我了
since I started looking like him.
很奇怪  是不是
It's weird, right?
那个医生是凯莉·尼曼吗
Was the surgeon Kelly Nieman?
是的  她是最棒的
Yes. Man, she is the best.
她还为艾米做了一点小整形
She even did a little touch-up on Amy.
可问题是  你要怎么证明
You know, the problem is, how are you gonna prove
你是迈克尔·布德罗呢
that you are Michael Boudreau?
你怎么证明我不是呢
How do you prove I'm not?
探长  有一个意想不到的情况
Detective. An unexpected development.
我们只有一份泰森的指纹复印件
We only have one hard copy of Tyson's fingerprints.
是的  监狱档案里的...
Yeah, from the prison records --
-我让他们寄过来了  -没错
- The ones I had them send here. - Right.
但是那些指纹和我们关押那个人的指纹
But those prints don't match the prints
并不相符
of the man we have in custody.
那不可能啊
That's impossible.
检测指纹的时候  比对出的结果是谁
Uh, when you ran the prints, whose name came up?
迈克尔·布德罗
Michael Boudreau.
我们反复验证过了  没有错误
We checked and rechecked. There's no mistake.
我知道他是怎么做的
I know how he did it.
泰森杀了布德罗  占了他的身份
Tyson killed Boudreau, took his identity.
凯莉·尼曼把布德罗的指纹移植到泰森手上
Kelly Nieman grafted Boudreau's fingertips onto Tyson's hands.
那样的话指纹卡上会显示出疤痕的
The scars would've shown up on his fingerprint card.
凯莉·尼曼的医术足以不留下任何疤痕
Kelly Nieman's good enough not to leave scars.
那些理论不能作为证据  卡塞尔先生
Theories don't help us, Mr. Castle.
检察官刚才打电话来
The D.A. Just called.
他们接到了布德罗律师的电话
They heard from Boudreau's lawyer,
他说我们以虚假的罪名扣押他的当事人
who says that we're keeping his client under false pretenses.
那是谎言  长官  那个人就是杰瑞·泰森
That's a lie, sir. That man is Jerry Tyson.
那我们怎么证明
Then how do we prove it?
泰森的DNA样本已经无法证明了
Not with Tyson's DNA sample.
样本已经遗失
That's missing.
而且据检察官所知
And as far as the D.A. is concerned,
泰森冲下桥时已经死了
Tyson died when he went off the bridge.
所以泰森案件的文档
This is why Tyson had his case files
以及他所有的记录都丢失了
and all his records taken --
所以他可以杀人之后逃之夭夭
for a clean slate so he can kill and get away with it.
你是说我们必须释放那个人吗  长官
Are you saying that we have to release that man, sir?
除非我们能证明他是泰森
Unless we can show that he's Tyson
或者说他与谋杀有关  否则就必须放人
or connect him to the murder, I'm afraid we have to.
-你在开玩笑吗  -真希望是
- You have to be kidding me. - I wish I was.
泰森要被移去拘留室
Tyson's getting moved to holding,
不过他的下一个目标可能在本区以外
but his next move might be outside of this precinct.
除非我们能证明他有罪或证明他是泰森
Unless we can tie him to a crime or prove that he's Tyson.
他做了那么多坏事
After all this guy's done,
我们必须做点什么将他绳之以法
there's got to be something we can do.
去查他卡车的GPS
Check the GPS on his truck.
找出他都去过哪里
Let's find out where he's been,
调出他公寓的所有通话记录
and pull all the phone records from the apartment.
我们必须找出点什么来
We got to find something,
任何可以使他与苏珊·瓦茨的死
anything that'll connect him Susan Watts' murder
或艾米·巴瑞特的失踪相关的线索
or Amy Barrett's disappearance.
离释放他还有多长时间
How much time do we have before we have to cut him loose?
盖茨正设法稳住检察官
Gates is trying to stall the D.A.,
所以我们只有一个小时或两个小时
so we got an hour, maybe two.
我们在这里无法证明
Here we are not being able to prove
那个泰森就是泰森
that Tyson is Tyson
因为他的DNA样本被他偷走了
because we don't have his DNA sample that he stole.
除非这个人就是麦克·布德罗
Unless this guy is Mike Boudreau.
那就可以解释他的指纹和他所说的话
Could explain the fingerprints, all he's been saying.
那是什么意思  泰森真的死了
Which would mean what? That Tyson is actually dead
而凯莉·尼曼把布德罗整成了泰森的样子吗
and Kelly Nieman cut Boudreau to look like Tyson?
不  他就是杰瑞·泰森
No. This guy is Jerry Tyson.
让我跟他谈  激怒他
I want to talk to him, rattle him,
让他暴露出本来的面目
get him to reveal himself.
我同意卡塞尔
I'm with Castle.
我认为那个人不是迈克尔·布德罗
I don't think that man is Michael Boudreau.
根据什么
Based on what?
我们确定布德罗和艾米·巴瑞特的身份后
Once we I.D. Boudreau and Amy Barrett,
我就开始监视他们的信用卡活动
I started monitoring their credit-card activity.
布德罗的卡刚刚在
Boudreau's card was just used
市中心的朱利叶斯咖啡屋消费过
to make a purchase at Caffee Julius in midtown.
找出真正的迈克尔·布德罗
Finding the real Michael Boudreau
可能会给我们需要的突破
might give us just the break we need.
好像角色互换了  是不是
Kind of a role reversal, isn't it?
-不太明白你在说什么  -你当然明白
- Not sure what you mean. - Oh, sure you do.
离你来这里探望我也没隔多久
Wasn't so long ago you were in here visiting me.
你又把我错认成泰森了
You got me confused for Tyson again.
你当时穿着警察制服
You were dressed in a police uniform,
而我就在你现在所处的位置
and I was in there where you are now.
别人都以为我喜欢的是杀人
People think it's killing that I like,
其实杀人只是一个结果
but murder's just an act.
最刺激的是你的期望
It's all about the anticipation,
你的计划
the planning,
潜伏到你的生活中
being inside your life,
想到你的这一切都会被我毁掉
knowing that I'm gonna take it all away from you.
这才是我喜欢的部分
That's what I like.
那会是一种什么感觉呢
What a feeling that must've been --
那种控制别人的感觉
That kind of power over someone.
是什么样的感觉  杰瑞
How does it feel now, Jerry?
我明白  你认为我是杰瑞·泰森
Look, I get it -- you think I'm Jerry Tyson,
我知道这都是我自找的
and I guess I brought that on myself.
不过你找错发泄对象了  知道吗
But you are jaw jacking with the wrong guy, okay?
我是麦克·布德罗
I'm Mike Boudreau.
为什么都是金发女人
Why the blondes?
艾米·巴瑞特  苏珊·瓦茨
Amy Barrett, Susan Watts.
我喜欢金发女人  不过我说了
I-I like blondes, but like I said,
我不  我不认识苏珊·瓦茨
I don't -- I don't know who this Susan Watts is.
我猜  理由跟
See, I'm betting the reason
我在汽车旅店时说的一样
goes back to what I said at the motel.
你还真是一点都不了解我呀
You really don't know me at all, do you?
你是被单亲母亲带大的
You were raised by a single mother.
她一头金发
She was blond.
很是漂亮  但是...
She was beautiful, but...
她根本就不想要你
She never wanted you.
你被送去寄养  可惜不是什么好人家
You go into foster care, the bad kind.
你如此地憎恨
You have so much hate.
你痛恨你母亲抛弃你
So much hate towards your mother for abandoning you
所以你杀了这些女人来报复她
that you kill these women to get back at her.
我说的对吗
Was I right?
一切都因妈妈而起
Is this all about mommy?
就是因为你母亲
It is about your mother.
全都是因为你母亲
This is all about your mother.
对不起  莱恩  我堵车了
I'm sorry, Ryan, I got caught in traffic.
布德罗可能早已经走了
Boudreau is probably long gone by now.
不一定
Not necessarily.
他刚在朱丽斯咖啡馆点了一份科布沙拉
He ordered a Cobb Salad at Cafe Julius.
说不定正坐在那里吃呢
So he may be in there eating.
好吧  我去看看  一会打给你
Okay. I'll check. I'll call you back.
等等  艾米·巴瑞特
Wait, Amy Barrett!
等等  等等  我有话要对你说
Wait -- wait, I need to talk to you.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是贝克特探长
I'm Detective Beckett.
-别烦我  -不  等等
- Leave me alone. - No! Wait.
我们一直在找你
We've been looking for you.
对  麦克的律师说过你会来找我
Yeah. Mike's lawyer told me you'd show up.
他叫我不要跟你说话
He said not to talk to you.
你刚才是不是用了他的信用卡
Did you just use his credit card?
麦克给过我授权
Mike gave me permission.
你所认识的迈克尔·布德罗其实是杰瑞·泰森
The man that you know as Michael Boudreau is Jerry Tyson.
他是个杀人狂魔
He is a serial killer,
你会成为他的下一个受害者
And you will be his next victim.
走开
Back off.
这是我的名片  艾米  给我电话
That's my card, Amy! Call me!
给我走开
Stay the hell away!
-喂  -我想到了
- Hey. - I got it.
我想到怎样拿住泰森  关键就是他的母亲
I know how we can nail Tyson. The key is his mother.
他妈妈怎么了
What about his mom?
泰森的出生证明丢了
Tyson's birth certificate is missing.
这也不奇怪
No surprise there.
但当年他妈妈送他去寄养的时候
But his mother signed the papers
是她签署的文书
when she dumped him into foster care.
我们对比他俩的DNA  就能证明他是杰瑞·泰森
We compare her DNA to his, we can prove he's Jerry Tyson.
她还活着吗
And she's still alive?
住在白平原  她叫格雷琴·卡特勒
And living in White Plains. Her name is Gretchen Cutler.
格雷琴·卡特勒
Gretchen Cutler?
是谁找我
Who wants to know?
贝克特探长  纽约警局  这位是卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett, NYPD. This is Mr. Castle.
我们想了解一些你儿子的情况
We need to ask you a few questions about your son.
我没有儿子
I don't have a son.
我们说的是杰瑞·泰森
We're talking about Jerry Tyson.
我知道你们说的是谁
I know who you're talking about.
他从九岁起就离开这里了
He hasn't lived here since he was 9.
他被送给别人寄养
When he was put into foster care.
我是个好妈妈
I was a good mother.
他变成现在这样跟我没关系
Nothing I ever did could've made him what he was.
他们说的那些都不是真的
The stuff they said was not true.
事实上  我们相信
Actually, we believe
有几起案子可能是错怪他了
that he was unjustly accused of several crimes.
没错  我们想证明他的清白
Yeah, and we are just looking to clear his name.
现在说这个有点晚了
It's a little late for that now.
知道对于杰瑞的一些说法
It might help you rest easy
是错误的  可能会让你宽慰些
Knowing that some of what was said about jerry is untrue.
我们只需要一份你的DNA样本
All we would need is a sample of your DNA.
没有用的
That won't do you no good.
杰瑞不是我亲生的
Jerry wasn't my blood.
-可登记的是你  -我也没办法
- You're listed as his mother. - Not by choice.
他是杰夫的孩子  当时他是我的男友
He was Jeff's kid. He was a boyfriend at the time.
杰夫离开后就再也没回来
Jeff took off and he never came back,
我又能怎么办
so what was I gonna do?
我试着给杰瑞一个幸福的家
I tried to make this a happy home for Jerry.
我尽可能的多照顾他
I looked after him as long as I could,
但他总惹是生非
but he was a hellion.
天生就这样
He was born that way.
他变成现在这样跟我没关系
Nothing I ever did could've made him what he was.
你知道杰夫现在在哪
Well, do you know where Jeff is now
或者杰瑞的生母在哪吗
or Jerry's biological mother?
死了  都死了
Oh, dead, both of them.
你还留着他的旧物吗
Do you still have any of his things,
比如牙刷  梳子什么的
like a toothbrush or hairbrush?
没有  杰瑞几年前回来过
Nothing like that. Jerry came by years ago,
他逼我把所有以前的东西都给了他
and he made me hand over everything that was ever his.
你没留下任何他的东西吗
And you didn't keep any of his belongings?
一点都没有吗
Nothing at all?
我也不能让他全拿走
Well, I couldn't let it all go.
我还藏了一些留作纪念
I tucked away a few keepsakes.
能给我看看吗
Mind if I take a look?
他妈妈看起来可真是个圣人
His mom sounds like a real saint.
是啊
Yeah, agreed.
只有那些一直强调自己是好父母的人
Only people who keep insisting they're not terrible parents
才是糟糕的父母
are terrible parents.
都是些玩具
These are all just toys.
是阿  看样子也无法从上面提取DNA
Yeah, I don't think we can pull DNA from any of this.
这些都是杰瑞·泰森的玩具
But I mean, these were Jerry Tyson's toys.
看上去都很普通
They're just so normal.
你想看到什么  动物尸体  压扁的人头
What did you expect? Dead animals, shrunken heads?
不
No.
卡塞尔
Castle.
乳牙
Baby tooth.
他的牙齿
His tooth.
还有他的DNA
With his DNA.
我们拿定他了
We got him.
实验室正加急从牙齿上提取DNA
The lab is expediting DNA tests from the tooth.
初步结果一出他们就会联系你
They'll call you as soon as they have prelim results.
他们拿什么用作比较样本
Then what are they using as a comparative sample?
是我们在他家逮捕他时
Saliva from a beer that Tyson was drinking
他喝过的啤酒里的口水
when we busted him at the apartment.
那泰森也不知道我们在比对他的DNA
Then Tyson has no idea that we're running his DNA?
真是太棒  凯特
Oh, that's excellent, Kate.
长官  地检那边怎么办
Sir, where are we on the D.A.?
我已经说服他在结果出来之前
I convinced him to stall Tyson's lawyer
拖住泰森的律师
until the results came in,
我一有消息就会通知你
and I'll let you know when I hear something.
尼曼医生
Dr. Nieman.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我告诉过你照片里那人不是杰瑞·泰森
I told you the man in the photo wasn't Jerry Tyson.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
-等麦克·布德罗出来  -有意思
- Waiting for Mike Boudreau. - Interesting.
你跟他是什么关系
And what is your relationship with him?
他是个需要帮助的病人
He's a patient in need of support.
你可真是尽心尽力
Wow, you really go the extra mile.
麦克什么时候能放出来
How soon till Mike is released?
没你想得那么快
Not as soon as you were hoping.
泰森的律师坚持要我们放他出拘留室
Tyson's lawyers insisted we move him from the holding cell.
凯莉·尼曼在这
Kelly Nieman is here.
她在等他出来
She's waiting for him to be released.
我很期盼看到她极度失望的表情
I look forward to her profound disappointment.
我还记得他在旅店转变的时候
You know, I remember back at the motel when I saw him turn.
我知道了他是谁
When I knew who he was,
他也知道我知道了
and he knew I knew.
当我意识到时  太迟了
It all came to me a second too late.
我不断在脑海中重现那一刻
I've relived that moment so many times
知道
knowing that...
因我的过错  导致他逃跑  害人
my mistake set him free and cost people lives.
你差点成为其中一个
You were almost one of those people.
现在我有机会
And now I have a chance
把精灵放回瓶中
to help put the genie back in the bottle,
这是个很糟的比喻  他可不是精灵
Which is a terrible metaphor because that guy is no genie.
谁会希望从他身上得到三个愿望
Who'd want three wishes from him, right?
我是艾米  艾米·巴瑞特
Hey, it's Amy. Amy Barrett.
艾米  你还好吗
Amy! A-are you okay?
我看见她了
I saw her.
我在新闻上看到她了
I saw her on the news.
谁  你看见谁了
Who? W-who did you see?
死掉的女孩  长得像我那个
The girl that died... that looked like me.
苏珊·瓦茨
Susan Watts?
艾米  你认识她吗
Amy, did you know her?
你对她有任何的了解吗
Do you -- do you know anything about her?
你是因为这个逮捕了麦克吗
Is that why you arrested Mike?
因为你认为他可能...
'cause you think he could've...
艾米  他对你说过关于她的事情吗
Amy, did he ever say anything about her?
他提及过她的名字吗
Did he ever mention her name?
没有
No.
但我看见他们在一起过
But I saw them together.
什么时候
When?
三天前
Three days ago.
麦克开着那辆卡车
Mike was driving the truck.
她和他在一起
She was with him.
我以为他出轨了  但现在...
I thought he was cheating on me, but now...
我害怕
I'm afraid.
害怕很正常  你处境的确危险
And you have every reason to be.
但是艾米我能保护你  你现在在哪
But, amy, I can protect you. Where are you now?
第九大道和珍街街角
Corner of 9th Ave. and Jane Street.
别走开  我马上过去
Don't move. I'll be there, okay?
好
Okay.
-我跟你一起去  -不  卡塞尔
- I'll go with you. - No, castle.
我不想吓到她
I don't want to scare her off.
她是唯一能够将苏珊·瓦茨和谋杀
She's the only person that might be able
和泰森联系起来的人
to connect Susan Watts' murder to Tyson.
老天  她可真有种啊  出现在这里
Man, she's got some brass ones, doesn't she, showing up here.
坐下
Sit down, bro.
踱步不会让结果出来得更快
Pacing's not gonna make the results come any quicker.
我最近读到DNA时间久了会降解
I've been reading how DNA results degrade over time.
如果他们从牙上什么也没查到怎么办
What if they can't pull any from that tooth?
他们能从穴居人牙齿上提取DNA
They can pull DNA from a caveman tooth.
不会出问题的
It's not gonna be a problem.
还是心慌...
Still...
...等待让我很不安
...the waiting is killing me.
你怎么来了
What brings you here?
我只是想你可能需要人陪陪
I just, uh, thought you might like some company.
好啊  坐
Sure, why not? Pull up a chair.
我们在等什么
What are we waiting for?
不知道  也许是文书吧
I don't know. Probably just paperwork.
你去过白平原吗
You ever go out to White Plains?
没有
Can't say that I do.
我刚去过
I was, um, I was just out there.
我参观了你儿时的家
I saw your childhood home.
我遇见了格雷琴·卡特勒
I met Gretchen Cutler.
没听说过这个名字
I'm not familiar with that name.
你知道她说什么吗
You know what she said?
她说她所做的一切
She said nothing she ever did
都不会把你变成现在这个样子
could've turned you into what you are.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
我觉得这不是真的
'cause I get the feeling it isn't.
我觉得她是你第一个想杀的人
I get the feeling she's the first person you ever wanted to kill.
但那样做
But...that would be...
目的太暴露
too obvious.
最好还是猎杀长得像格雷琴的金发女人
Better to hunt blond women who look like Gretchen once did.
这样的话  她会在新闻上看到她们的脸庞
See, that way, she'd have to see their faces on the news
并知晓了你在杀害她们
and know that you're out there killing them
是因为她
because of her.
现在你把杀人的变态指数提高了
Now you've taken it to the next level, though, haven't you?
我找到了一张格雷琴·卡特勒
I, uh...came across this photo of Gretchen Cutler
年轻时的照片
when she was young.
苏珊·瓦茨和艾米·巴瑞特
Susan Watts and Amy Barrett...
跟她长得一样
look just like her.
凯莉·尼曼的功劳
Thanks to Kelly Nieman.
她给你提供了完美  顺从的被害人
She supplied you with perfect, compliant victims.
有多少个
How many were there?
肯定不止两个
Not just 2.
五个  10个
5? 10?
20个
20?
毕竟现在你不用猎杀她们了
After all, you don't have to hunt them anymore.
你圈养她们
You raised them...
像牲口一样
like livestock.
是你
It's you.
是的
Yes, it is.
如果这个"你"  指代的是麦克·布德罗
If by "you," you mean Mike Boudreau.
结果出来了
This is it, bro.
布德罗先生
Mr. Boudreau.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
这怎么可能
How is it possible?
牙上的DNA不匹配
The DNA from the tooth wasn't a match.
是他  我们知道是他
It's him. We know it's him.
艾德·特纳
Ed Turner.
他怎么了
What about him?
他是被认为发现苏珊·瓦茨尸体的那个人
The guy who supposedly found Susan Watts' body.
艾德·特纳
"Ed Turner."
那个名字是"归来"的变位词
That name -- it's an anagram for "returned."
也许那是巧合
Maybe that's a coincidence.
不  跟泰森有关的事  都不是巧合
No, it's not. There's no coincidence with Tyson.
他总是棋高一着
He's always one step ahead.
他想出现在这  于是他现身了
He wanted to be here. So did she.
为什么
Why?
总是转到语音留言
It keeps going to voicemail.
您已接通凯特·贝克特的语音留言
You've reached the voicemail of Detective Kate Beckett.
-怎么样了  -办成了
- Yes?  - It's done.